Simon Fraser University Faculty Association collection (Manfred Mackauer collector)
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Simon Fraser University Faculty Association collection (Manfred Mackauer collector)
1968 - 1979
F-185
Q106643838
19 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Mackauer, Manfred
Manfred Mackauer was a professor of biology at Simon Fraser University. He retired from his teaching duties in 1997.
published
Full
Revised
The title is based on the contents of the collection and the name of the collector.
From 1969 to 1970, Mackauer served as vice-president of the Simon Fraser University Faculty Assocation (SFUFA), and from 1970 to 1971 he served as SFUFA's president. During his time on the SFUFA executive, the university underwent a period of unrest culminating in the strike of eight faculty members in the Political Science, Sociology, and Anthropology (PSA) Department. After the Board of Governors fired three of the suspended professors and cancelled part of the university's document protecting faculty rights, the SFUFA executive called for a vote of non-confidence in the Board and SFU President Kenneth Strand. When faculty members rejected the executive's recommendation, Mackauer and three other members of the executive resigned.
Collection consists primarily of the SFUFA president's correspondence during the PSA crisis. In addition, there is some correspondence concerning other matters of interest to faculty members such as salary negotiations, pensions, and sabbatical leave. Records include correspondence, clippings, notes, minutes, legal statements, reports and other documents.
The material was arranged by the Archivist.
Mackauer, Manfred; Simon Fraser University Faculty Association; Department of Political Science, Sociology and Anthropology
The records were donated to the Simon Fraser University Archives by Manfred Mackauer in 2003.
All accessions have been processed as of January 2004. No further accruals are expected.
For other material relating to the Simon Fraser University Faculty Association, see the Finding Aid for F-79, Simon Fraser University Faculty Association.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
File and item lists are available.
- First CAUT censure, 1968; F-185-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 185-1)
  published
  Textual records
  Open
- Popkin decision, 1970; F-185-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 185-1)
  Pending review
- PSA dispute, vol. 1, 1970; F-185-0-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 185-1)
- PSA dispute, vol. 2, 1970; F-185-0-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 185-1)
- PSA dispute, 1970 - 1971; F-185-0-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 185-1)
- Correspondence - general (1970-1971, 1979), vol. 1, 1970 - 1979; F-185-0-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 185-1)
- Correspondence - general (1970-1971, 1979), vol. 2, 1970 - 1979; F-185-0-0-0-7 (Archival box - small 185-2)
- Correspondence - alphabetical, vol. 1, 1970 - 1971; F-185-0-0-0-8 (Archival box - small 185-2)
- Correspondence - alphabetical, vol. 2, 1970 - 1971; F-185-0-0-0-9 (Archival box - small 185-2)
- Newsclippings, 1971; F-185-0-0-0-10 (Archival box - small 185-2)